<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jayson Tian</title>
    <description>My blog site.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 11:47:14 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 11:47:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overthinking Thinking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thinking about something in endless circles — is exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While everyone overthinks a few things once in a while, chronic over-thinkers spend most of their waking time ruminating, which puts pressure on themselves. They then mistake that pressure to be stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are people who have levels of overthinking that are just pathological,” says clinical psychologist Catherine Pittman, an associate professor in the psychology department at Saint Mary’s College in Notre Dame, Indiana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But the average person also just tends to overthink things.” Pittman is also the author of &lt;em&gt;“Rewire Your Anxious Brain: How to Use the Neuroscience of Fear to End Anxiety, Panic, and Worry.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overthinking can take many forms: endlessly deliberating when making a decision (and then questioning the decision), attempting to read minds, trying to predict the future, reading into the smallest of details, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who overthink consistently run commentaries in their heads, criticising and picking apart what they said and did yesterday, terrified that they look bad — and fretting about a terrible future that might await them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘What ifs’ and ‘shoulds’ dominate their thinking, as if an invisible jury is sitting in judgement on their lives. And they also agonise over what to post online because they are deeply concerned about how other people will interpret their posts and updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They don’t sleep well because ruminating and worrying keep them awake at night. “Ruminators repetitively go over events, asking big questions: Why did that happen? What does it mean?” adds Susan Nolen-Hoeksema, the chair of the department of psychology at Yale University and the author of &lt;em&gt;Women Who Think Too Much: How to Break Free of Overthinking and Reclaim Your Lif&lt;/em&gt;e. “But they never find any answers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you consistently focus on ruminating and make it a habit, it becomes a loop, And the more you do it, the harder it is to stop. Clinical psychologist Helen Odessky, Psy. D., shares some insight. “So often people confuse overthinking with problem-solving,” says Odessky, the author of “&lt;em&gt;Stop Anxiety from Stopping You.&lt;/em&gt;” “But what ends up happening is we just sort of go in a loop,” Odessky says. “We’re not really solving a problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overthinking is destructive and mentally draining. It can make you feel like you’re stuck in one place, and if you don’t act, it can greatly impact on your day-to-day life. It can quickly put your health and total well-being at risk. Rumination makes you more susceptible to depression and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people overthink because they are scared of the future, and what could potentially go wrong. “Because we feel vulnerable about the future, we keep trying to solve problems in our head,” says David Carbonell, a clinical psychologist and author of “&lt;em&gt;The Worry Trick: How Your Brain Tricks You into Expecting the Worst and What You Can Do About It.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extreme overthinking can easily sap your sense of control over your life. It robs us of active participation in everything around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Chronic worriers show an increased incidence of coronary problems and suppressed immune functioning. Dwelling on the past or the future also takes us away from the present, rendering us unable to complete the work currently on our plates. If you ask ruminators how they are feeling, none will say “happy.” Most feel miserable,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2017/03/pressure-doesnt-have-to-turn-into-stress&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; Nicholas Petrie, a senior faculty member at the Center for Creative Leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overthinking can trap the brain in a worry cycle. When ruminating become as natural as breathing, you need to quickly deal with it and find a solution to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When an unpleasant event puts us in a despondent mood, it’s easier to recall other times when we’ve felt terrible. That can set the stage for a ruminator to work herself into a downward spiral,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.realsimple.com/work-life/life-strategies/get-over-overthinking&quot;&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt; Amy Maclin of Real Simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-defeat-this-pattern-of-thinking-and-win-your-life-back&quot;&gt;How to defeat this pattern of thinking and win your life back&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chronic worrying is not permanent. It’s a mental habit that can be broken. You can train your brain to look at life from a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To overcome overthinking, Pittman recommends you replace the thought. “Telling yourself to not to have a certain thought is not the way to not have the thought,” she says.”You need to replace the thought.” What if she were to tell you to stop thinking about pink elephants? What are you going to think about? That’s right: pink elephants. If you don’t want to think about a pink elephant, conjure up an image of, say, a tortoise. “Maybe there’s a big tortoise holding a rose in its mouth as it crawls,” says Pittman. “You’re not thinking about pink elephants now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk yourself out of it by noticing when you’re stuck in your head. You can tame your overthinking habit if you can start taking a grip on your self-talk — that inner voice that provides a running monologue throughout the day and even into the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can cultivate a little psychological distance by generating other interpretations of the situation, which makes your negative thoughts less believable,” says Bruce Hubbard, the director of the Cognitive Health Group and an adjunct assistant professor of psychology and education at Columbia University. This is called &lt;em&gt;cognitive restructuring&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself — What’s the probability that what I’m scared of will actually happen? If the probability is low, what are some more likely outcomes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it’s a problem you keep ruminating about, rephrase the issue to reflect the positive outcome you’re looking for,” suggests Nolen-Hoeksema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Instead of “I’m stuck in my career,” tell yourself or better still write, “I want a job where I feel more engaged.” Then make a plan to expand your skills, network, and look for opportunities for a better career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find a constructive way of processing any worries or negative thoughts, says Honey. “Write your thoughts down in a journal every night before bed or first thing in the morning — they don’t have to be in any order. Do a ‘brain dump’ of everything on your mind onto the page. Sometimes that can afford a sense of relief, “ recommends Honey Langcaster-James, a psychologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also control your ruminating habit by connecting with your senses. Begin to notice what you can hear, see, smell, taste, and feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to reconnect with your immediate world and everything around you. When you begin to notice, you spend less time in your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also notice your overthinking habit and talk yourself out of it. Becoming self-aware can help you take control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pay a little more attention,” says Carbonell. “Say something like: I’m feeling kind of anxious and uncomfortable. Where am I? Am I all in my head? Maybe I should go take a walk around the block and see what happens.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognise your brain is in overdrive or ruminating mode, and then try to snap out of it immediately. Or better still, distract yourself and redirect your attention to something else that requires focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you need to interrupt and replace hundreds of times a day, it will stop fast, probably within a day,” says Dr Margaret Weherenberg, a psychologist and author of &lt;em&gt;The 10 Best-Ever Anxiety Management Techniques. &lt;/em&gt;“Even if the switch is simply to return attention to the task at hand, it should be a decision to change ruminative thoughts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes practice, but with time, you will be able to easily recognise when you are worrying unnecessarily, and choose instead, to do something in real life rather than spending a lot of time in your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, convert, “I can’t believe this happened” to “What can I do to prevent it from happening again?” or convert “I don’t have good friends!” to “What steps could I take to deepen the friendships I have and find new ones?” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/ryanhowes/how-to-stop-ruminating&quot;&gt;recommends&lt;/a&gt; Ryan Howes, PhD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get lost in thoughts about what you could have, would have, and should have done differently. Mental stress can seriously impact your quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overactive mind can make life miserable. Learning how to stop spending time in your head is one of the greatest gifts you can give yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all habits, changing your destructive thought patterns can be a challenge, but it’s not impossible. With practice, you can train your brain to perceive things differently and reduce the stress of overthinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If overthinking is ruining your life, and if you think you may be spiralling into depression because of your thoughts, it pays to get professional help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/life/2019/12/05/integrity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/life/2019/12/05/integrity.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Smart People Do Stupid Things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my life, I have had the privilege of working with many incredibly talented, ambitious, and intelligent individuals across various industries. There is no shortage of smart people in this world, yet surprisingly there is no shortage of stupid decisions, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this the case?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/2019/01/how-not-to-be-stupid/&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Shane Parrish, Adam Robinson notes that stupidity is not the opposite of intelligence: “In fact, stupidity is the cost of intelligence operating in a complex environment. It’s almost inevitable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly two years ago, I was presented with a unique opportunity to advise on what might have become one of the most extravagant music festivals of our time. Fueled by an ingenious marketing campaign that tapped into the modern millennial zeitgeist, Fyre Festival completely sold out after only a few days. However, with just one month to go until showtime, management was still seeking consultants to help with production. That’s when they found me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this, you likely already know &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-46904445&quot;&gt;how that story ended&lt;/a&gt;. I was hired as a consultant to try to rescue what is now one of the most highly publicized failures in our cultural memory. Many intelligent people were involved and of course, many stupid decisions were made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Russell_Lowell&quot;&gt;James Russel Lowell&lt;/a&gt;: “One thorn of experience is worth a whole wilderness of warning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I hope that sharing my experience (and utilizing the mental model of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IAmAdamRobinson?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor&quot;&gt;Adam Robinson&lt;/a&gt;), might be enough to help you (the reader) make better decisions in the future, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-stupidity-checklist&quot;&gt;The Stupidity Checklist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Acting alone any of these are powerful enough, but together they dramatically increase the odds you are unaware that you’ve been cognitively compromised.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Shane Parrish, Farnam Street&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Robinson defines stupidity as overlooking or dismissing conspicuously crucial information. I believe that stupidity arises when one acts out of alignment with one’s internal compass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how prepared or how smart you might be, the presence of any one of the following seven factors can lead to stupid decisions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being outside of your comfort zone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rushing or urgency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stress, fatigue, or illness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixation on an outcome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information overload&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being in a group where social cohesion matters (susceptible to “group think”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being in the presence of an “authority”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Literally all of these factors were present during my time at Fyre:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were living out of our comfort zone in a foreign country and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;working on an urgent timeline (probably six months too short).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were stressed and as the festival drew near, we were running on little to no sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the end, we were fixated on producing an event, any event,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and we were overwhelmed by the number of variables that continued to stack against us.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We contractors were united in our mission of not wanting to let each other down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were in the presence of an authority who held the final veto on all decisions and who would not take no for an answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many nights, I’d ask myself, “How the hell did I get here?” When it was all said and done, I asked myself, “Why did I stay?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-con-artists-do&quot;&gt;What con artists do&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Con artists capitalize on our inherent psychological and emotional flaws. And since we are all human, we all have them. Perhaps we hold dreams of unparalleled success or a desire for untold riches. Otherwise, we may have deep-rooted self-doubt or an uncontrollable sense that we are not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I agreed to work on Fyre, I carried this sort of psychological baggage with me, which helped lead me into the maelstrom. More specifically, I was fixated on an outcome (see number four above), and my self-doubt helped to turn an unlikely character into an authority figure in my life (see number seven).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is proven that any of the factors in the above checklist can contribute to stupid decisions, I believe that these two, in particular, may be the most destructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“As the ignorant perform their duties with attachment to results, similarly the learned may also act, but without attachment, for the sake of leading people on the right path.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— The Bhagavad Gita, Chapter 3: Karma Yoga, Verse 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us cling to overly-ambitious dreams that are hard to release. I have always carried what I sometimes call my “delusion of grandeur.” When I was a child, I wanted to be the president of the United States or a famous actor. Random? Or is there something these two have in common? I recognize that in those childhood dreams there was desire to be recognized by others for greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teenager, I quickly learned that in our society, one of the most valued measures of greatness is wealth. If you are a self-made millionaire (or better yet, a billionaire) in the United States today, then you have won “the game.” Your wealth becomes the points you post on an imaginary scoreboard that proves your worth to your peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fixation on the dual outcomes of greatness and riches helped to make me an easy target for a con artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have always carried what I sometimes call my “delusion of grandeur.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I was asked to join the Fyre Festival team, my second startup, 90sFest, was teetering on the edge. I was now facing what I then believed to be my second major failure in life, and I had the credit card debt to prove it. My self-confidence was broken, and I felt that I badly needed to post a win on that societal scoreboard. This put me in a dangerous position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first heard of Fyre Festival, I laughed. My intuition said that there would be no way for them to pull off a festival of that scale on a remote island in four months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But only one month later, like many of you, I saw the infamous promo video. I witnessed many of my own peers scrambling to find now sold-out tickets so that they could participate in this once-in-a-lifetime event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, struggling financially, self-confidence at a nadir, and fixated on rerouting my career, I was introduced to Fyre Festival founder Billy McFarland. After our first phone call, I was captivated. I could already visualize my future success: It looked just like the promo video but I was there, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would contribute to one of the most special events of our time, achieving public greatness and repute. I would repay all of my credit card debt. The icing on the cake was that if the festival were a success, I might be asked to join one of the hottest tech startups in a leadership role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fixated on this outcome. I could see myself with my new influencer friends, the money in my bank account. I could feel my reputation on the rise. As a result, though the production challenges were seemingly insurmountable with one month left until showtime, I started to believe that I could help them fix the mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we desire something so strongly that we become blind to the problems in front of us and the character of those around us, in spite of our own intuition, that’s a sign of trouble to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;objectifying-the-authority&quot;&gt;Objectifying the authority&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What the superior man seeks is in himself; what the small man seeks is in others.” — Confucius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us trust others more than we trust ourselves, and so we seek validation from the external. I believe that from a young age, we are programmed to feel this way. The external is offered to us as a measurement of how well we are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his work &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spiritualityandpractice.com/book-reviews/view/9499/paths-to-god&quot;&gt;Paths to God&lt;/a&gt;, Ram Dass explains this phenomenon much better than I can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To socialize a child, you need to instill in him only three basic principles: to accept his information from the outside; to look outside for his rewards; and to ignore his inner voice if it conflicts with what comes from outside authority. That’s the way you train a child to be a member of a society — so that when Mother says, “Do this,” you do it, even if in your heart it doesn’t feel right. If you get good enough at doing that, you become a “success” in the society; if you don’t, you’re an outcast.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there I am, at the tail end of two failed startups, flat broke, and right in front of me is the opportunity to change my fate. The man (boy) offering me this chance is someone who seemingly has everything that I desire: the money, the success, and the respect of some of the top minds in the business world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instantly, I trust him more than I trust myself. I assimilate his vision of success into my own and ignore all of the red flags right in front of my eyes — especially the impossible task of producing anything near the marketing videos that Fyre had released only one month before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take the bait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours after signing my agreement with Fyre, I join my first production call and more signs of dysfunction quickly arise: missed payments, delayed orders, and last minute changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Anyone can become an authority on any subject when we do not trust ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I have a sense that I shouldn’t go to the Bahamas, but the #FOMO is too strong. If I turn this offer down and the festival is a success, I’ll forever ask “What if?” Plus, it’s only four weeks of my life. What’s the worst that could happen? That we can’t pull it off in time and cancel? One day later, I’m on a flight from Los Angeles to Great Exumas, and well, you know the rest of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that when we suffer from low self-confidence, sometimes caused by factors outside of our control, we actually seek the authority figure. Anyone can become an authority on any subject when we do not trust ourselves. The presence of an authority figure allows us to minimize our cognitive load by deferring responsibility to the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, we begin to objectify the authority. The closer we get, the more we see their flaws, but we still ignore them. We get closer, but further away at the same time. This distance helps us reserve the right to later tear down these false idols, knowing all along that we have ourselves to blame for the position we give them in our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the con artist has established his position of authority over you, It’s too late. You are in his grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moving-on&quot;&gt;Moving on&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been over two years since my brief four weeks on Great Exumas working on Fyre, and it has taken quite a bit of effort to put the past behind me. The resurgence of interest created by the “dueling documentaries” on Netflix and Hulu extended my reflection. For that, I am grateful. These films also helped to raise awareness for the local workers who were negatively impacted. There is still a live GoFundMe campaign to support them and you can donate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/the-exuma-foundation-for-victims-of-fyre-festival&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fyre was an intense, and at times painful, experience for the contractors (like me) who were not paid, the guests who were misled, and the local Bahamians who were left to clean up the mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet it also offers many invaluable lessons and warnings. In a phrase: Learn from my mistakes so you don’t have to live them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was inspired by my own experience at Fyre Festival as well as one of my favorite podcast conversations between &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IAmAdamRobinson?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adam Robinson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/farnamstreet?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shane Parris&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;h for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Farnam Street blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; (a must read, or &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/the-knowledge-project/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, if you don’t already subscribe) called &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/2019/01/how-not-to-be-stupid/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Not to Be Stupid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story is part of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/human-parts/art-of/home&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Art Of&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, an ongoing series that supplies you with instructions for living.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/psychology/2019/12/05/art-knowledge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/psychology/2019/12/05/art-knowledge.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>psychology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Useful Bio Review Link</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;https://www.jj-sct-bio.com/uploads/2/4/6/5/2465445/ap_chap_9_guide.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/misc/2019/12/04/biology-text-link.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/misc/2019/12/04/biology-text-link.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Biochemistry Review</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;biochemistry-review-questions&quot;&gt;Biochemistry Review Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;How common are the elements that living systems are made out of?  What are these elements?&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&amp;gt; Hydrogen, Carbon, Oxygen, Nitrogen

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Explain the cause of molecular polarity. &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&amp;gt; Molecular polarity occurs when there is an unequal sharing of covalent bonding electrons between two non-metals. When one has a greater/stronger electronegativity (hold of electrons) than another, a polar bond occurs.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Why are radioactive elements useful for the study of biological systems?  &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&amp;gt; Scientists can tag specific molecules without alternating the structure or function of the studied compounds.   

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Explain how the structure of water molecules account for each of the following properties and are useful for living systems.  &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

| **Property of Water**                   | **How does H2O molecular structure  account for this property?** | **Where / How is this property useful for  living systems?** |
| --------------------------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------ |
| Cohesion                                | Attraction of  water to itself due to hydrogen bonds         | Surface tension: eg. Water strider                           |
| Adhesion                                | Water is polar  and climbs on surfaces that are more polar than itself | Capillary action (water in xylem)                            |
| High Specific  Heat                     | Takes lots of  thermal energy to break hydrogen bonds        | Minimizes changes in temperature (water used to distribute  heat) |
| Specific heat of  Vaporization          | Takes high energy  for hydrogen bonds to be broken into gas  | Evaporative cooling (kinetic energy leaves body, average  kinetic decreases hence cooler. |
| Floating Ice                            | As water is  frozen it expands making it less dense          | Ice floating to keep organisms alive in the winter           |
| -      Good  Solvent Properties         | -      Due to  polarity water is able to form electrostatic interactions with other polar  molecules or ions. | -    Carries valuable material and  nutrients, minerals for organisms |
| -      Dissociation  of Water Molecules | -      Allows  dissociation of salt, ions, and other polar molecules | -    Leads to acids and bases  which allows pH alteration    |

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Why is carbon central to the structure of all biological molecules?   &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&amp;gt; It has four valence electrons which means it can form single, double, and triple bonds! That means many elements can bond to it. Carbon-carbon bonds are extremely strong.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;What are functional groups and why are they important in biochemistry?&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&amp;gt; They act as chemical motifs and their presence allows us to predict properties and behaviours of those molecules.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/details&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/misc/2019/11/11/biochemistry-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/misc/2019/11/11/biochemistry-review.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Definition of Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;achievement-oriented-learning&quot;&gt;Achievement Oriented Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been thinking a lot about personal growth and achievement. Though the adage of how the journey is more beutiful than the destination is true, it can’t be denied that sometimes the outcome does matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me personally, I have always been more of an achiever kind of guy more than the journey for about as long as I’ve known my goals for. There’s the obvious truth and feeling that you are the ‘best’ when you have the greatest achievement. It is this type of thinking that has shaped our classrooms, work environments, and current society. We are always striving higher, competing with each other to see who has more achievement or a better outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong- competition can be beneficial and great in its own way, but it’s the balance between self-growth and achievement that’s is the most difficult to obtain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-development&quot;&gt;Self-Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been reflecting on my self-development goals for the past week. I realized how misleading our academic culture can be in this time and age. All of us, as students of some sort, are so accustomed to the achievement-oriented mentality that we often forget the reason behind our motives and actions. To learn, is to experience and understand something unbeknownst to you. At school, especially in competitive environments, we find ourselves seeping into the sinkhole of mindless learning - we don’t think but only remember and regurgitate information to obtain the high marks. When that happens, I believe that we begin to perceive learning opportunities as tasks. We act to fulfill the purpose of completion while disregarding the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is natural to be competitive. As human beings, most of us have egos that makes us believe we are superior to others. But truth said, there must be a line drawn between healthy and unhealthy competition. I now think that it’s important for a student to recognize whether the learning environment they are in is beneficial or harmful to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we are under so much pressure and stress that all we see In our head is a never ending todo list that needs to be completed, I believe one must take a break and rewind their thoughts. It is that balance between how much of the external pressures a student wants to internalize that decides upon whether they learn for self-development or result.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/life/2019/11/09/learning-defintion.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/life/2019/11/09/learning-defintion.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ELISA Testing of Lyme Disease</title>
        <description>&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#interpreting-elisa-tests&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-interpreting-elisa-tests&quot;&gt;Interpreting ELISA Tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) is a test that uses enzymes and colour changes to identify a substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be used to identify specific surface markers or metabolites associated with particular diseases. Different variations of the ELISA test exist, but one of the most common protocols involves the sandwich method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Known monoclonal antibodies are affixed to wells in a plate (these are the ‘capture antibodies’)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A sample to be tested is added to the wells and any antigens present will bind to the appropriate capture antibody&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The plates are then washed to remove any unbound antigen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A second set of monoclonal antibodies linked to colour-changing enzymes are then added to the wells&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These ‘detection antibodies’ will bind to any antigens captured, creating a sandwich (antibody - antigen - antibody)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The wells are then washed again to remove any unbound detection antibodies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When an appropriate substrate is added to the wells, the enzyme-linked detection antibodies will trigger a colour change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only wells in which a sandwich complex has formed will show a colour change, hence identifying the presence of an antigen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ib.bioninja.com.au/_Media/elisa_med.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interpreting-elisa-tests&quot;&gt;Interpreting ELISA Tests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ELISA tests can be used to diagnose disease conditions based on the presence of disease markers (antigens, metabolites)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samples taken from infected patients will induce a colour change when treated with appropriate detection antibodies
The amount of colour change can be used to signify rate of disease progression (more marker = more colour change)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/biology/2019/11/06/lyme-disease.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/biology/2019/11/06/lyme-disease.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Diseases and Global Warming</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read an article writing about how new diseases are popping up from random places never seen before. Apparently, they have a significantly higher viral resistance than other common bacteria, and 75% of treatment and vaccines are ineffective against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought it was interesting as most diseases these days can be treated pretty easily. The article did not seem to cite or credit where they got the statistics so I did a little bit of digging on the internet and discovered that these types of bacteria actually carry ancient viruses that are rarely seen present day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cycle of life and evolution is actually pretty dope. We evolve to become resistant to many pathogens through immune response and B lymphocytes but in return, the pathogens – bacteria and viruses evolve and develop new strats to infect us again. This coexisting cycle seems to be continuous until most of us die from disease or we manage to kill off the disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, for now in the 21st century most of us are safe from any deadly virus raging to infect us and kill us, but will it always be like that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists have started to discover certain forms of archaic viruses from places of the most unimaginable. These include underground caves miles deep with no sunlight 24/7 (anaerobic bacteria), mummies from pyramids, and one fairly recent location of discovery: the arctic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course we see the cliché ice cap melting and polar bear cub dying commercial and also hear about our sea levels rising but nobody has really considered another big effect of global warming: What would happen when we are suddenly exposed to the outbreak of nocuous diseases and prehistoric viruses that most modern vaccines have no effect on? Well, we basically have a post-apocalyptic world. Damn, what if the viruses were zombie diseases and we basically have a real life Walking Dead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s actually the thought of how nobody is concerned about all this that is actually scary. Most people believe that they won’t be affected as long as they are far away. Well, think about the Walking Dead again 🧟‍♂️. In 2007, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/earth/story/20170504-there-are-diseases-hidden-in-ice-and-they-are-waking-up&quot;&gt;a group of scientists revived a 8 million year old bacterium frozen in dormant ice at Beacon Valley in Antarctica&lt;/a&gt;. Honestly, the entire point is to show that the melting of ice will ultimately release terrible difficult-to-treat viruses into our international population and infect most people. Some of us will be able to become resistant and fight it off while some of us may die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short, don’t contribute to global warming 🔥&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I read on permafrost melting: [article here]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/biology/2019/08/17/global-warming-diseases.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/biology/2019/08/17/global-warming-diseases.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>biology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vacationing in Ontario</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Though Ontario seems like a pretty cold place during the winter and the busy city of Toronto has many things that may be quite typical or sometimes boring, there are actuall many places in Ontario that have more spotlight on mother nature and provide for a wilderness vacation outlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoyed most in the summer times, the following places are literally in our backyards! There’s no need to travel to another province or country when you only have one week of summer left for vacationing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Blue Mountains, Collingwood&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bruce Peninsula, Tobermory&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sauble Beach&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saugeen Shores&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point Farms Provincial Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goderich, Ontario&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bayfield, Bluewater&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grand Bend, Lambton Shores&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Websters Falls, Dundas Peak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;image-20190824193933495&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop 1: Blue Mountain Resort
Typical resort with attractions such as hiking, treetop trekking, great food, and possible camping sites. There is also a mountain coaster and village for shopping. Perfect summer time resort to relax at for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop 2: Town of Tobermory
Tobermory is a harbour village on the Bruce Peninsula in the province of Ontario. Just southeast, Bruce Peninsula National Park is known for the Bruce Trail footpath on the craggy Niagara Escarpment, and the Grotto, a wave-carved cave in Georgian Bay. The village lies next to Fathom Five National Marine Park, which is home to the Flowerpot Island sea stacks, 19th-century lighthouses and multiple shipwreck dive sites. Order of travel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singing Sands [40 minutes]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Peninsula National Park [4 hours]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fathom Five National marine Park [3 hours]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop 3: Sauble Beach
Sauble Beach is a beach community and unincorporated area in the town of South Bruce Peninsula, Bruce County, in the northern area of southwestern Ontario, Canada. It is on the Bruce Peninsula, along the eastern shore of Lake Huron, on the north edge of the Saugeen Nation. The beach takes its name from that given by early French explorers to the sandy Sauble River, originally “La Rivière Au Sable” also indicating that the river emptied into Lake Huron at a sandy beach. The river was labelled with the French name on maps until 1881, when it became the Sauble River; in early years, a sawmill was built on the river, and later, a hydro electric plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop 4: Saugeen Shores
Saugeen Shores is a town in Bruce County, Ontario, Canada, formed in 1998. On January 30, 1998, the provincial government amalgamated the Towns of Southampton and Port Elgin, together with Saugeen Township, to form the Town of Port Elgin-Saugeen-Southampton. On December 17, 1998, the Province renamed the entity as the Town of Saugeen Shores. The primary employment categories are agriculture, small business, tourism and work at the Bruce Power nuclear power station. The population doubles in the summer due to cottagers and campers who arrive in the area. Close to MacGregor Point Provincial Park, the town has several beaches on Lake Huron. In addition to the two main population centres of Southampton and Port Elgin, the town includes a portion of the village of Burgoyne and the North Bruce area, straddling the municipal eastern and southern boundary respectively. In 2016, the permanent population of Saugeen Shores was 13,715, in a land area of 171.05 square kilometres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop 5: Town of Goderich
Goderich is a town in the Canadian province of Ontario and is the county seat of Huron County. The town was founded by John Galt and William “Tiger” Dunlop of the Canada Company in 1827. First laid out in 1828, the town is named after Frederick John Robinson, 1st Viscount Goderich, who was British prime minister at the time. The town was officially incorporated in 1850. As of the Canada 2016 Census, the population is 7,628 in a land area of 8.64 square kilometres. Located on the eastern shore of Lake Huron at the mouth of the Maitland River, Goderich faces the lake to the west and is notable for its sunsets. Some claim that Queen Elizabeth II once commented that Goderich was “the prettiest town in Canada” although no reigning monarch has ever visited Goderich. The town indicates that tourism is among its important industries. It has been named one of Ontario’s best small towns by Comfort Life, a website for retirement living in Canada. The town participates yearly in the Communities in Bloom competition; and has won awards in many categories. In 2012, Goderich was a National Finalist in the competition, and was also part of the Circle of excellence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop 6: Bayfield, Bluewater
Bayfield is a community in Bluewater, Ontario, Canada in Huron County with a 2016 population of 1,112. It is on the eastern shore of Lake Huron at the mouth of Bayfield River. Bayfield is a popular tourist destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop 7: Grand Bend
Grand Bend is a community located on the shores of Lake Huron in Southwestern Ontario, Canada. It is part of the Municipality of Lambton Shores in Lambton County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinery Provincial Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grand Bend Beach&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horse Winery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lambton Heritage Museum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image result for grand bend beach&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop 8: Websters Falls
A beautiful trail hiking along a mountain up to Dundas peak, which is where the scenery of trees captures the view of many hikers. This is a great spot for viewing Hamilton as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/life/2019/06/12/vacation-summer-ontario.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/life/2019/06/12/vacation-summer-ontario.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rambling About Arbitrary Topics</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;customizing-your-jekyll-theme&quot;&gt;Customizing your Jekyll Theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default styles try to be basic, but they’re still far too stylized for my liking. We’re going to override all the styles and make them much more simple. You can turn off the Jekyll serve at this point and just start saving files. We’ll go from top to bottom alphabetically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using my own name as an example, but obviously change everything to match you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hello&quot;&gt;Hello&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jekyll, &lt;strong&gt;_includes&lt;/strong&gt; are files that should show up on every page - header, footer, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;footerhtml&quot;&gt;footer.html&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;headhtml&quot;&gt;head.html&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;head&lt;/code&gt; metadata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;headerhtml&quot;&gt;header.html&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your navigation and header. I will dynamically load all pages into the navigation bar, except for the blog page, which I will load manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;layouts&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;layouts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The layout that your content will conform to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;defaulthtml&quot;&gt;default.html&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pagehtml&quot;&gt;page.html&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the dashes at the top are &lt;strong&gt;mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don’t include them, the website won’t work properly. For pages and posts, the default layout gets loaded, plus any additional layout information you desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;posthtml&quot;&gt;post.html&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same as the page, but with date and author metadata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pages&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default Jekyll website does not come with a &lt;strong&gt;_pages&lt;/strong&gt; directory, but I like to include it so the main directory stays clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;01_aboutmd&quot;&gt;01_about.md&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we’re creating the markdown files. Prepending them with a number ensures that they appear in the order you specify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;02_contactmd&quot;&gt;02_contact.md&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;_posts&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to leave the post exactly as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delete about.md from the main directory, since we’ve put it in the &lt;strong&gt;_pages&lt;/strong&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;indexhtml&quot;&gt;index.html&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.html&lt;/strong&gt; in the main directory will be the main page of the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blog&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new directory called &lt;strong&gt;blog&lt;/strong&gt;. Inside, create an &lt;strong&gt;index.html&lt;/strong&gt;. This will be the main blog page that will contain all your posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;css&quot;&gt;css&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;css&lt;/strong&gt; directory in the root should contain one file - &lt;strong&gt;main.scss&lt;/strong&gt;. Edit it to contain the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-scss highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave the top part exactly as is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;_sass&quot;&gt;_sass&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The absolute last directory that we need to edit - the sass partials. Create each of these files in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_sass&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;_basescss&quot;&gt;_base.scss&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Variables, mixins, and resets will go here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-scss highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;_syntax-highlightingscss&quot;&gt;_syntax-highlighting.scss&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply remove this line from the file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-scss highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;_layoutscss&quot;&gt;_layout.scss&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All my styles will go in here. I made a simple, responsive website that doesn’t rely on any frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-scss highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;serve-jekyll&quot;&gt;Serve Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, all the files are ready and jekyll can be served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you inserted all the code exactly as above, the sass partials will compile into the main.scss. All the rest of the files will write to &lt;strong&gt;_site&lt;/strong&gt; site, which is the distribution folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Server running… press ctrl-c to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I make a change to any of the sass files, they should compile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-terminal highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pushing-jekyll-site-to-github-pages&quot;&gt;Pushing Jekyll site to GitHub pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create an empty repository in GitHub. Mine is &lt;strong&gt;startjekyll&lt;/strong&gt;, so the Git repo URL is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://github.com/taniarascia/startjekyll&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one change that needs to be made in order to have one site for both your local Jekyll and the live GitHub pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duplicate your &lt;strong&gt;_config.yml&lt;/strong&gt; and call it &lt;strong&gt;_config_dev.yml&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave the &lt;strong&gt;_config_dev.yml&lt;/strong&gt; as is, and change &lt;strong&gt;_config.yml&lt;/strong&gt; for the live site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-yaml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when you want to work on the site locally, you will run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it will load the information from the dev config.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve your Jekyll one last time to ensure all the final changes have been updated. Here are the commands to push the site to GitHub pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensures that you’re on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch, not &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Track all files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commit all files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/life/2015/11/30/first-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/life/2015/11/30/first-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
